HENRY CHEN

in linkedin.com/in/henrychen-tw | M: +886952890993 | holyman1010@gmail.com | Portfolio: https://goo.gl/A6kOPL

Profile

User-centered product designer with over 10 years of experience in structuring, developing, and implementing digital design strategies. Innovative use of technology and CRO to drive user experience and achieve business goals. Be good at coordinate cross-function to complete projects efficiently and satisfy customers with intuitive, user-friendly designs.

Areas of Expertise

- Conversion rate optimization
- Strong collaborative skills
- User interface design skills
- Front-end programming skills
- Project management
- User research and interview skills
- Digital marketing analytics and optimization
- Excellent problem-solving skills

Work Experience

Digital Experience Lead

July 2021 - Present

China Development Financial - Taipei City, Taiwan

- Drive design across the organisation through appropriate usage of design methods and delivering digital experiences.
- Support the head of department in championing a customer-centric design culture;
 maintaining high levels of productivity and engagement in the design function.
- Prioritize initiatives and user stories to support business plans and timelines.

Design Producer

Feb 2020 - June 2021

Gogoro - Taipei City, Taiwan

- Managing design project, work-back schedules, design deliverables, and coordinate resources.
- Utilizing various tech or non-tech approaches to enhance the collaboration within the design team.
- Helping creative team to collaborate better as well as with cross-functional teams and external creative partners.

Product Design Lead (4 direct reports)

Apr 2017 - Feb 2020

AsiaYo.com - Taipei City, Taiwan

- Develop, implement, and lead the company's design strategy.
- Transform high-level business strategies into a practical action plan.
- Utilize monitor tools to conduct CRO and user experience optimization.

Sr.UI/UX Designer

May 2016 - April 2017

HongKu info Co.,Ltd - Taipei City, Taiwan

- Prioritizing project deliverables and assigning, reviewing, and approving work.
- Creating low/high fidelity prototypes and conducting user testing.
- Defining UI in a clean, well structured, and easily maintainable principle.

SAP - Taipei City, Taiwan

- Conduct user research with stakeholders to analyze business needs and goals.
- Serve as a dynamic function role to support the different stages of the project.
- Collaborate with the development team to implement the design system for the product.

UI/UX Design Lead

Jan 2014 - Sep 2014

PChome Online Inc. - Taipei City, Taiwan

- Responsible for high-quality designs, graphics, mockups for digital product.
- Design, develop and implement design guidelines.
- Collaborate with product management and engineering to deliver a well-thought user experience.

Senior Web Designer

Mar 2011 - Dec 2013

Gameflier International Corporation - Taipei City, Taiwan

- Create the website's visual imagery and ensuring it is in line with company branding policy.
- Design gaming graphics, animations, and post-production digital photographs.
- Plan and produce enticing motion graphics for video deliverables.

Graphic Designer

Dec 2009 - Dec 2010

ShSpa Inc. - Taipei City, Taiwan

- Create visual elements such as images and illustrations to deliver the product key selling points.
- Design layouts, including a selection of colors, images, and typefaces.
- Produce visual content on social media to attract traffic and fan interaction.

Education

National Taiwan University of Science and Technology

Master's degree, Industrial and Information Design 2020 - 2022 (expected)

National Taiwan Ocean University

Bachelor of Engineering (BEng), Department of Merchant Marine 2003 - 2008

Technical skills

Research, Information Architecture, Wireframing, Mockups, Prototyping, Team Management, Conversion Optimization, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Javascript Sketch, Photoshop, Illustrator, AfterEffect